Brecht, Arnold; Papers ger024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1905-1976; 2; 319 file folders
  The correspondence files span a period of over 70 years, with the bulk of the correspondence dating from the years 1933-1976. The correspondence has been arranged alphabetically within several categories: family, professional and general, students, politicians and public officials (U.S. and Germany), administrative and faculty members of the New School for Social Research, and organizational correspondence. The professional and general correspondence includes substantial amounts between Brecht and Julie Braun-Vogelstein, Jürgen Fehling, Carl Joachim (Achim) Friedrich, Kurt von Fritz, Ernest Hamburger, Ernest Hocking, Fritz Morstein-Marx and Gustav and Lydia Radbruch, as well as with former students Morris Forkosch and Alfred J. Jung. The collection also contains correspondence with the American statesman John Foster Dulles, as well as lengthy exchanges with German statesmen Otto Braun, Heinrich Brüning, Ferdinand Friedensburg and Theodor Heuss. The series also contains Brecht's correspondence with other members of the New School for Social Research, most notably with former New School Deans Alvin Johnson, Hans Simons and Hans Staudinger.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Family members, 2.1
    - Barthels, Dorothea (niece), 1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Brecht, Marie (née Weishaupt, mother), 1909 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Brecht, Gustav (brother), 1909; 1945-1948; 1955-1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Brecht, Gustav. Copies of affidavits, 1945 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Brecht, Rolf (brother), 1945-1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Schnirlin, Gertrud (née Brecht), sister, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, 2.2
    - A -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Adolph, Hans J. L., 1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Albert, Heinrich F. & Ida, 1933-1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Alexander, Edgar, 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Almond, Gabriel A., 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Anderson, William, 1940-1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Andrea, Erich & Fritz, 1948; 1950 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Angell, Ernest (Council for Democracy), 1943 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Anspach, Ernst, 1945-1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Archiv für Rechts- und Sozialphilosophie, 1955-1956 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1960; 1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Arnold, Fritz W., 1959-1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Ascher, Charles S., 1941-1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Aussenpolitik, 1955 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - B -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Baerensprung, H.W., 1945 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Baerwald, Friedrich (Thought), 1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Balasundaram, Palayam M., 1951-1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Banse, Herman, 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Barth, Eberhard, 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Barth, Max, 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Bauer, Friedrich, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Bausch, Hans A., 1955 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Bay, Jürgen, 1966-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Bayerische Rundfunk, 1955-1956 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1942-1948 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Beck, Earl R., 1957-1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Behn, Fritz, 1933 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Behn, Irmgard, 1952-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Behn, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Benda, Emanuel, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Benda, Gabi, 1948; 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Benda, Christian, 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Bergsträsser, Arnold, 1946; 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Berman, David, 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Bernsdorf, Wilhelm (Wörterbuch der Soziologie), 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Berolzheimer, Josef, 1934-1955 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Bilfinger, Käthe, 1968-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Blencke, Erna, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Borsig, Tet Arnold von, 1968-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Bracher, Karl, 1956-1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Brammer, Karl, 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Brand, Hanna, 1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1936-1939 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1940 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1941-1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1946-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Brenner-Rademacher, Susanna, 1964; 1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Breunig, Else, 1959-1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Brockhaus, Paul, 1964 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Brodersen, Arvid, 1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Brodie, William, 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Brook, Warner F., 1945 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Bülow, Andreas von, 1958; 1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Bundesarchiv Koblenz, 1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Burdine, J. Alton, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1934; 1936; 1939 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Byrnes, Eugene H., 1939 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - C -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Cahn, Edmund, 1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Caldwell, Lynton K., 1953 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - California Law Review, 1941 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Catlin, George E. Gordon, 1959-1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Chaudhry, Iqbal Nath, 1962-1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Claussen, Dean O., 1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Coker, Francis W., 1945-1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Cole, Taylor, 1946-1950; 1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Colegrove, Kenneth, 1946-1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Cook, Thomas I., 1953; 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Corwin, Edward S., 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Crome, Otto, 1953 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - D -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Daetz, Maria Mercedes, 1950-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Daetz, Lily, 1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Demeter, Karl, 1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt, Stuttgart, 1969-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Dimrock, Marshall E. (Immigration and Naturalization Service), 1940-1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Donnell, Dorothy, 1941 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Dorn, Herbert, 1952-1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Dorpalen, Andreas, 1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Dotzauer, Dina, 1957-1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - ds production (Dieter Schmidt), 1968-1970 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Duarte, Paulo (Anhembi, Saõ Paulo), 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Duggan, Stephen, 1943 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Duncan, John Paul, 1960-1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Durham, Henry C., 1956-1957; 1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Dunner, Joseph, 1945-1946; 1962-1965 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
      Including Brecht's contributions to the Dictionary of Political Science.
    - E -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Ebenstein, William, 1939 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Eberhard, F., 1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Eckardt, Wolfram von, 1945 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Eckener, Hugo, 1934-1935 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Ehrmann, Henry W., 1945-1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Emge, Carl A., 1948; 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Engisch, Karl, 1957-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - English, Raymond, 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Erdmann, Karl Dietrich, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Erler, Adalbert, 1946 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Eschenberg, Theodor, 1953-1976 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Esslinger, William, 1956 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Ewers, Hans, 1959; 1962 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Eynern, Margarete von, 1967 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - F -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
    - Fackelträger Verlag, 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Fairman, Charles, 1946-1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Faul, Erwin, 1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Fay, Sidney B., 1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Fehling, Jürgen, 1905-1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Feiler, Marie, 1953-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Fetscher, Iring, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Finer, Herman, 1943-1948 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Flechtheim, Julius & Helene, 1949-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Fleming, William, 1960-1963 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Flemming, Arthur S., 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Flotow, Rose Marie von, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Forkosch, Morris, 1951-1975 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1952; 1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Freund, Ludwig, 1947 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Frick, Heinrich, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Fried, John H. E., 1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Friedman, Bruno, 1958-1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Friedrich, Carl Joachim (Achim), 1934-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Friedrich, Manfred, 1966 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Fritzsche, Klaus, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Fritz, Kurt & Louise von, 1953-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - G -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Gaus, John M., 1940-1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Gillespie, S. Hazard & Ruth, 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Globus, Joseph & Grete, 1946; 1955 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Glum, Friedrich, 1954-1955 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Goldsmith, Arthur J., 1941 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Goldstein, Naomi, Wayland Vaughan, Gordon Allport, 1943 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Gotthard, Walther & Helene, 1949-1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Grabowsky, Adolf, 1941; 1956-1961 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Grathoff, Richard, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Gray, McGregor, 1961-1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Gropius, Walter & Ilse, Undated; 1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Grossmann, Kurt R., 1950-1960 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Grunebaum, L. H., 1940-1956 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Grzesinski, Albert C. (Association of Free Germans Inc), 1942 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Guenther, Peter W., 1958 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Gumbel, [Emil J.], 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Gunst, Dietrich, 1953-1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Guradze, Heinz, 1959-1972 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Gurwitsch, Aron, 1967 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - György, Antalffy, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - H -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Haig, Robert M., 1940-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Hallowell, John H., 1945-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Hamburger, Ernest, 1943-1976 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Hartmann, Heinz & Dora, 1954-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Harvard Law Review, 1941-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Harvard University, 1936-1940 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Haskell, Henry S., 1934 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Haussmann, Conrad, 1921 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Haussmann, Hermann, 1948-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Hazard, John N., 1947-1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Hebal, John J., 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Heberle, Rudolf, 1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Heimann, Hugo, 1944; 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Heimpel, Hermann, 1956; 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Heller, Gertrud, 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Helmolt, Bernd von, 1951 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Henle, G., 1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Hennig, E., 1967; 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Hermens, Ferdinand A., 1942-1977 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Herring, E. Pendleton, 1938; 1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Herrmann, Gertrude, 1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Herz, Else, 1953-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Herz, John H., 1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Hesse, Artur (Gewerkschaft Deutscher Beamtenbund), 1949-1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Carl Heymanns Verlag KG, 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Hippel, Fritz von, 1954-1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Hirsch, Felix E., 1944-1976 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Hirsch, Julius, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Hocke, Gustav René, 1934; 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Hocking, (William) Ernest, 1940-1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Höpker-Aschoff, Hermann, 1934-1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Holborn, Hajo, 1943 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Holcombe, Arthur N., 1938-1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Holmes, John H., 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1963; 1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - I - J -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Igel, Konrad (concerning Walther Rathenau), 1943-1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Iwand, Hans / Gurian, [Waldemar], 1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Jackh, Ernest, 1945; 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Jacobsohn, Peter S., 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Jaffe, Emy, 1968 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Jaffe-Richthofen, Else, 1959-1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Janovsky, Hannah Salomon, 1967; 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Jellinek, Walter, 1952-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Junz, Alfred J., 1950-1964; 1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - K -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Kann, Robert A., 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Kaufmann, Felix & Else, 1946-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Kaufmann, Walter H., 1950; 1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Kelsen, Hans, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Kemble, E. D. (General Electric Company), 1959-1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Smiddy, Harold F. "Research -- And Shaping the Future of Management", Undated; typescript (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Kempner, Robert M. W., 1941-1947; 1963-1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Kennan, George, 1952; 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Kessler, Friedrich, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Kiepenheuer & Witsch (Verlag), 1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Kirchheimer, Anne, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Klepper, Otto, 1940-1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - New England Christian Committee for Refugees, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Kline, Reamer ( Bard College), 1961; 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Knieriem, August von, 1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Koch-Weser, Erich & Irma, 1942-1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Kohn, Hans, 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Kohn, Walter S. G., 1957-1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Kolbe, Dieter (concerning Erwin Bumke), 1971 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Krayer, Otto & Ruth, 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Külz (Senatspräsident beim Bundesverwaltungsgericht), 1958-1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Kürschners Gelehrtenkalender, 1959; 1968 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Kunkel, Wolfgang, 1949-1950; 1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Kutscher, Irmgard & Hans, 1953-1973 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - L -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Lambie, Morris B., ca. 1940s (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Landau, Martin, 1963-1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Lang, Reginald D., 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Lasswell, Harold D., 1942; 1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Lazar, Joseph, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Lederer, Gertrud, 1958; 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Leibholz, Gerhard, 1953-1959 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Lepawsky, Albert, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Leser, Norbert, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Leval, Hilde Peltzer, 1959-1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Leyden, Victor von, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Liang, His-Huey, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Lichtenstein, Walter, 1937-1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Liebman, Charles J. (Refugee Economic Corporation), 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Lindheim, Hermann von, 1952-1955 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Lins, Mario, ca. 1970s (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Lippincott, Benjamin E., 1947; 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1941; 1950; 1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Litchfield, Edward H., 1945; 1949-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Litt, Theo, 1939-1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Littauer, Lucius N., 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Loewenstein, Karl, 1941-1947; 1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Löwith, Karl, 1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Lohmann, Friedrich, 1951; 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Luckemeyer, Ludwig, 1966 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Luther, Hans, 1934; 1955; 1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - M -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Mack, Arien (Social Research), 1975 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Macmahon, Arthur W., 1942-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Macridis, Roy C., 1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Mainzer, Otto, 1941; 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Mann, Golo, 1961 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Mann, Katia, 1955-1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Mann, Thomas / Fritz Behn, 1931 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Marburg, Gertrude (Mrs. Louis C), 1966-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Martin, John, 1938-1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Marx, Hugo, 1943 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Marx, Werner, 1958-1972 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Mason, Lester B., 1946; 1952 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Mattern, Hans W., 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - McClelland, Charles A., 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - McCollum, Dudley F., 1934 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - McLachlan, Donald, 1970 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Mehnert, Klaus, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Melamid, Alexander, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Mende, Dietrich, 1953-1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Menzel, Hans & Emmy (née Severing), 1947-1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Menzel, Christiane, 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Merriam, Charles E., 1936-1940 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Mestern, Hans, 1951-1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1945 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Miller, Susanne, 1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Mirkine-Guetzévitch, Boris & Eugenia, 1946-1956 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Montaño, Salvador M. Dana, 1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Morstein-Marx, Fritz, 1936-1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Müller, Hildegard & Hans, 1961-1965 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Müller-Seidel, Walter, 1955-1957 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Munro, Dana G., 1944-1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Murmann, Ernst, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Musgrave, Richard A., 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - N, O -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Nash, Arnold, 1954 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Nass, Otto, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Natanson, Maurice, 1963; 1968 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - The National Archives (Dorsey W. Hyde Jr), 1941 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Needler, Martin, 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Die Neue Zeitung, 1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Neumann, Sigmund, 1944-1953 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Newman, K. J., 1960 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Norddeutscher Rundfunk, 1969 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung, 1953-1963 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Odum, Howard W., 1942-1943 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Ogg, Frederic A. (American Political Science Review), 1934-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)